Omar KADIS

Tel: 226-246-3916

Email: omarkadish@gmail.com Location: Windsor, ON N8X 3Z9

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/omar-kadish/

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic developer with a flair for teamwork! Armed with **critical thinking** skills and a strong focus on user experience, dedicated to delivering **top-quality** web projects that exceed expectations. Whether it's **optimizing** web performance or **contributing** to team success, I'm always up for a challenge and committed to delivering exceptional results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- Laravel
- PHP
- Web Development
- jQuery
- Ajax
- OOP
- MySQL

- Git / GitHub
- Front-End Skills
- API Development
- C#
- Agile Development
- Ionic framework
- Visual Studio

- ASP.NET
- Detail-oriented
- Well organized
- Flexible
- Arabic
- Turkish
- Video Editing

EXPERIENCE

Production Associate Cottam Diecasting Ltd – Windsor, ON

Dec 2022 - June 2023

- Worked with hand to safely operate and set up production equipment.
- Managed the quality of finalized products and inspected for unsatisfactory parts before packing and shipping.

Web Developer Rikaz Software Development (Remote)

Feb 2022 - May 2022

- Provided the company with a solution to organize their customer subscriptions and systematized reminders of the subscription statuses with an email notification system.
- Summarized the subscriptions in an interactive visualized chart.
- Implemented advanced customizations of the **CRUD** operations UI.

Laravel Web Developer Intern Sanliurfa Metropolitan Municipality

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

- Developed a web application from scratch utilized primarily on Laravel PHP framework and MySQL including UI and admin panel with flexible functionality.
- Produce clean and well-structured code, with detailed specifications.
- Successfully completed every task and was approved by the supervisor.

Junior Windows Application Developer Rikaz Software Development

Feb 2018 - Oct 2018

- Learned to write well-formatted code to develop websites based on the requirements.
- Gained experience in working in an Agile-based company and participated in teamwork.

 Participated in building Windows applications utilized on WPF and XML using MVVM design pattern.

EDUCATION, COURSES & TRAINING

Associate Degree in Computer Programming 2019 – 2022 Ankara University

- **Built a full server-side Blog project and CMS** with PHP for the 3rd semester's System Analysis and Design class.
- learned **OOP** Principles, and **MVC** Software Design Pattern.
- Improve Front-End programming skills (HTML, CSS, JavaScript).
- Entity and ASP **DotNet** Frameworks.
- Amassed knowledge to design the **database structures** for each system I develop.

Emotional Intelligence (Alfaisal University), June 2023

Introduction to Agile Development and Scrum (IBM), April 2023

Learning How to Learn by Deep Teaching Solutions (Coursera), February 2023

Build a Business Blog using WordPress (Coursera), July 2022

CISCO Cybersecurity Essentials, June 2022

Business Club Training (Turkish Labor and Employment Agency) (ISKUR), May 2021

PHP Laravel Bootcamp (Kodluyoruz Academy), March 2021

Design Thinking (UNHCR and Habitat Association), Oct. 2020

PROJECTS

Resume Builder

 A Laravel package to manage and display an online resume, it can be built with the admin panel.

Blog Site

 Blog project, an online journal that presents a record of contents, and a gallery, built with PHP and MySQL.

School Management System

• Full School Management System that manages students, teachers, classes, subjects, and many more utilized with Laravel PHP Framework.

MyNote app

• A note-taking app utilized Ionic Framework for the UI and PHP as the backend.

Innovative Solutions for Social Cohesion Hackathon

• Participated in the Social Cohesion Hackathon. Design and plan for an employmentoriented project by analyzing the given data.

Culture And Informatics Web Project

 Web Application built using PHP Laravel Framework, with a flexible interface and admin panel to control the contents in the app.

VOLUNTEERING

- **Volunteer translator** at Turkish Red Crescent Community Center (2019 2022).
- **Team member** in Community Volunteers Foundation (TOG) (2021 2022).